Guide to the Richard Bruce Nugent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1880s-1986; Series XI; 7 boxes + 1 broadside folder
  - Delany, Samuel R., 1 Snapshot (3.7" x 3.5") (Box 86)
    Delany is pictured with his wife, Marilyn Hacker, and an unidentified Black man
  - de Marco, John, 1 Studio Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 86)
    Commercial nude physique photograph by Vulcan Studios. One corner bent & chipped,; small portion of the emulsion missing. The defects do not affect the image.
  - De Sola, Helen Winner, 1940s ?, 1978; 3 Photographs (various sizes) (Box 86)
  - de V------, A------, 1979; 2 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 86)
    Two photographs of the chief of police of Vega Baja (Puerto Rico) asleep nude, with his considerable endowment plainly visible.
  - di Carlo, Tom, 1968; "2 Photographs 3.3" x 4.2"; 8 Photographs 5" x 7" 9 Photographs 8" x 10"; 3 Proofs 8" x 10"" (Box 86)
    Nude physique photographs by Bernard Kay
  - Dirty Pictures, ca 1900-1920; "18 Photos (3.5" x 5.5" & smaller) 2 Drawings" (Box 87)
    Commercial porno from another era.
  - Duran, Angel, 1 Snapshot (Box 87)
    By Nugent. Duran was Nugent's roommate in Hoboken.
  - Ellington, Duke, 1 glossy studio photo (8" x 10") (Box 87)
  - Freeman, Wilbur, ca 1945; 1 Photo with Paper Frame (Box 87)
    Inscribed to Nugent on the frame.
  - Eng, Lonnie, 1 Photo (8" x 10"); 13 Photos (5" x 7") (Box 87)
    Nude photographs of a beautiful young man by Bernard Kay
  - Eng, Lonnie & Mike Miranda, 8 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 87)
    Erotic/pornographic photographs of two young men in the nude by Bernard Kay
  - Garber, Eric, 1 Snapshot (Box 87)
    Garber with Dennis Weaver (roommate) & Craig Garber
  - NO FOLDER (Box 87)
  - Gumby, L. S. Alexander, 1953; 1 Photograph (5" x 7") (Box 87)
    Inscribed "To my most worthy Friend, Brfuce / N.Y. Hospital, Dec. 2nd 1953
  - Harvey, Georgette, 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 87)
    Inscribed "To My Pal Bruce / From / /Your Pal / Georgette / "Ah Dear". Harvey was in the cast of Porgy with Nugent. She later starred in Mamba's Daughters on Broadway.
  - Hernandez, Osvaldo ("Cano"), "12 Photographs (8" x 10"); 7 Photographs (5" x 7") 2 Photographs (4" x 5")" (Box 87)
    Photographs of a beautiful young man, many nude, by Bernard Kay. One of the photographs was used by Nugent as the basis for a painting, "Cano" (Current whereabouts unknown).
  - Horne, Lena, 1 Photograph (10" x 8") (Box 87)
    Horne with [TV personality?] 1/2" abrasion, Pinhole, short crack. Overall very good(-).
  - Horwood, Mary, 1920s; 2 Photographs (3" x 2") (Box 87)
  - Huey, Richard, ca 1929; 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 87)
  - Hughes, Langston with Elmer Jackson & Carlton B. Norris, 1962; 1 8" x 10" Publicity Photograph (Box 87)
  - Jackman, Harold, ca 1929; 1 Studio Portrait (Box 88)
    Photo by James L. Allen. Inscribed "For Bruce / From Harold". Paper lightly age-toned, else fine.
  - Jenkins, Raymond, 3 Enlarged Snapshots (8" x 10"); 1 Snapshot (3.3" x 5") (Box 88)
  - Jeter, William (Billy Clark), 1 Headshot (8" x 10"); 3 Snapshots (various sizes) (Box 88)
    Jeter was an aspiring singer, a protégé of Bernard Kay. The headshot is slightly soiled on the verso.
  - Jeter Family, 1 Studio Portrait (10" x 8") (Box 88)
    Group portrait of six young men and two young women. Individuals unidentified. Poor condition--creased and torn, with two corners missing.
  - Lanning, Ensign B., 1940s; 1 Snapshot (Box 88)
    Labelled on the verso "Ensign B. Lanning / U.S.S. Oklahoma
  - Lindemann, Kelvin, 1 Portrait (7" x 9.4"); 4 Snapshots (Box 88)
    The portrait and two snapshots are inscribed to Nugent. With a business card on which Lindemann has written "'Politiken' Copenhagen" and an address.
  - Locke, Alain, 1929; 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 88)
  - Mayo, George, 3 Snapshots (Box 88)
    Nugent met Mayo in Rome.
  - Mayor, Gus, ca 1955; 14 Photos (8" x 10") (Box 88)
  - McClendon, Rose, 1 Studio Portrait (9.5" x 7.7"); 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 88)
  - McGill, James, ca 1973; 2 Headshots (8" x 10") (Box 88)
    Enclosed in a letter to Nugent from Bernard Kay 8/13/1973.
  - Melis, John (Son of), 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 88)
    Spotted and soiled. Melis was Nugent's friend and his landlord when he moved to Hoboken
  - Mendez, Santiago (Chago), 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 88)
    Nude with an erection. Out of focus
  - Miranda, Angel, 14 Snapshots (Box 88)
    3 of the photos are of Miranda; the rest are by him. All taken in Korea.
  - Miranda, Jose, 1959; 2 Photos (8" x 10") (Box 88)
    Pornographic photos of Miranda with an erection, taken in San Juan. Probably taken by Bernard Kay.
  - Miranda, Mike, 3 Photographs (10" x 8") (Box 88)
    Miranda is nude. Photos by Bernard Kay.
  - Morelli, Joseph, 1944; 1 Snapshot (Box 88)
    Inscribed to Nugent and dated on the verso
  - Mossman, May, 1949; 4 Photographs (4" x 5"); 1 Studio Portrait (4" x 5") (Box 88)
    All inscribed and dated by Mossman
  - Jamaica [Queens] NAACP Day Care Center, 1970; 3 Photographs (10" x 8") (Box 88)
    Children at the facility. Stamped "Cecil Layne Photo, Inc." Waterstained
  - Niggeratti Manor, 1942; 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 88)
    NYC Municipal Archives "Tax" Department Photograph of 237 W. 136th St
  - Nugent, Bruce & Philander Thomas, 1929; 3 Snapshots (2" x 3.4" & 1.5" x 2.4" (Box 88)
    On board ship to England. 2 Photos of Nugent with Thomas; 1 of Nugent with unidentified child.
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1936; 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 88)
    Nugent with the bust of Antinous, Hadrian's favorite. Photograph by Carl Van Vechten, with his blind stamp. Condition: near fine. Encapsulated.
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1930s; Mounted Photograph (2.5" x 4.8") (Box 88)
    Self Portrait. Mounted on a 7" x 8.7" board.
  - Nugent, Bruce (Nude), 2 Small Snapshots (2.5" x 3.8") (Box 88)
    One snapshot depicts Nugent and two other men lying nude on a bed. Encapsulated, soiled.
  - Nugent, Bruce and Grace Nugent, ca 1952; 1 Photograph (5" x 7") (Box 88)
    Nugent and his wife on the street. Labelled on the verso "Richard / Bruce Nugent / Grace Nugent" in Nugent's hand. Unobtrusive black mark, very lightly tanned, else near fine. This photograph appeared in When Harlem was in Vogue by David Levering Lewis.
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1950s; Photograph (10" x 8") (Box 88)
    Nugent with a cat. Some spotting and soil.
  - Nugent, Bruce & Raymond Jenkins, ca 1955; 3 Snapshots (Box 88)
    Excellent photographs of Nugent & Jenkins on a Manhattan street. Fine
  - Nugent, Bruce & Angelo Perez & -----------, 1958; 7 Snapshots (Box 88)
    Nugent, Perez, and an unidentified third man on a rural outing
  - Nugent, Bruce, Grace Nugent and Raymond Jenkins, 1959; 7 Snapshots (Box 88)
    Scenes at a picnic
  - Nugent, Bruce, Grace Nugent, & Raymond Jenkins, 1950s; 17 Snapshots (Box 88)
    Excursion to upstate New York
  - Nugent, Bruce with James W. Thompson, 1972; Poloroid Snapshot with Copy (Box 88)
  - Nugent, Bruce & Friends, 1950s; 3 Snapshots (Box 88)
  - Nugent, Bruce, Various; 18 Snapshots (Box 88)
  - Nugent, Bruce, and Unidentified Friend in Rome, 1970s; 14 Snapshots (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1974; Copy of a Newspaper Photograph (8.5" x 5.8") (Box 89)
    Nugent at a party in Rome in 1974 with "Bamby" (a model) and Giuseppe Siragusa.
  - Nugent, Bruce; Antonio D'Ambrosio and Others in Rome, 1970s; 22 Snapshots (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce by George Mayo, 1974; 1 Snapshot set in a card (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce, Raymond Jenkins & Unidentified Friends, 11 Snapshots (Box 89)
    At a party.
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1982; 12 Photographs by Thomas Witrth (Box 89)
  - Nugent at College Language Association (CLA)Conventions; Others, including Gwendolyn Brooks and Maya Angelou, 1982, 1983; 7 Snapshots (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce with Louise Thompson Patterson, 29 May 1983; 4 Photographs (4" x 4") (Box 89)
    Taken at the book signing for Faith Berry's biography of Langston Hughes at Common Concerns bookstore in Washington, DC. In two of the photos, Berry is visible in the foreground. Photos by Thomas H. Wirth
  - Nugent, Bruce with Thomas Wirth, Eunice Weed, 4 June 1983; 4 Photographs, 4.5" x 4.5" (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce, 1983; 1 Snapshot (Box 89)
    Photo by S. Lord at the NABWMT convention in Columbus, OH.
  - Nugent at FIRE!! Book Signing, Common Concerns Bookstore, Washington, D.C., December 1983; 5 Photographs 4.5" x 4.5" by Thomas Wirth (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce & Others in Central Park, 1984; 5 Photographs 5" x 7"; 1 Photograph 3.5" x 3.5" (Box 89)
    4 Photographs of Nugent by Tom Wirth 1 Photograph of Nugent & Jesus Sanabria by Tom Wirth 1 Photograph of Nugent & Wirth by Jesus Sanabria
  - Nugent, Bruce at Brunch with Arnold Rampersad, Bruce Kellner, Eric Garber, Steven Jones, Jesus Sanabria, 22 April 1984; 29 Photographs by Thomas Wirth (Box 89)
    1 Photograph of Nugent 8" x 8" 4 Photographs 5" x 6" 24 Photographs 5.5" x 3.5"
  - Nugent, Bruce & Eric Garber, Tom Wirth, Arnold Rampersad, Steve Jones at Brunch in the Madison Cafe, Hoboken, 22 April 1984; "8 Color Photographs (6.1" x 3.5") by Bruce Kellner " (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce, Tom Wirth & Jesus Sanabria, 1984; 6 Photos (various sizes) (Box 89)
    At a gallery opening. Photos by Tom Wirth, except where he is a subject.
  - Nugent, Bruce. Metuchen, c 1985; 5 Photographs 3.5" x 3.5" by Tom Wirth (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce with Tom Wirth, Italo Vera in Restaurants, c 1985; 6 Poloroid Snapshots; 1 Snapshot 4.5" x 3.5" (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce & Bo Walker, 1980s; 4 Poloroid Snapshots (Box 89)
    At a gallery opening.
  - Nugent, Bruce in Plexus-Purgatorio Time, 1985; 16 Snapshots 3.5" x 5" (Box 89)
    Nugent as the Pope in the art installation Plexus-Purgatorio Time at Cuando, 9 Second Avenue, with other photographs of the event.
  - Nugent, Bruce & Daphne Arnstein, Arnstein Friend, Tom Wirth at Arnstein's Summer Home in the Berkshires, c 1985; "4 Snapshots 4" x 4" 12 Color Slides 2" x 2"" (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce and Clymenza Hawkins, c1985; "3 B & W Photographs 3.5" x 3.5" 1 Poloroid Snapshot" (Box 89)
    Taken at the Madison Cafe & a NYC restaurant.
  - Nugent, Bruce with Paul England, Raymond Jenkins, T. Wirth, c1985; "2 Color Snapshots 4" x 5" 3 Color Snapshots 3.5" x 5" " (Box 89)
    Taken at Paul England's home on the North Shore of Long Island.
  - Nugent 80th Birthday Party, July 2, 1986; 34 Photographs 4" x 6" by A'Lelia Bundles (Box 89)
  - Nugent 80th Birthday Party, July 2, 1986; 6 Photographs 5.5" x 4" by George Mayo (Box 89)
  - Nugent 80th Birthday Party, July 2, 1986; 15 Photos (4.4" x 3.5") by Fred LaFrance (Box 89)
  - Nugent 80th Birthday Party, July 2, 1986; 15 Photos (5.1" x 3.5") by Njambi McQueen (Box 89)
  - Nugent, Bruce Memorial Service, July 2, 1987; 10 Snapshots (5.1" x 3.5") (Box 89)
    Includes an announcement, a program of the service, and a key to the group photograph of the audience.
  - Nugent, Grace, Various; 2 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 90)
  - Nugent, Grace, 1951; 1 Studio Portrait (8" x 10") (Box 90)
    Photo by Ruth Andros, Albany NY, together with studio folder-frame, from which it has been removed. Inscribed "For Bruce with all my love -- / Grace / 11.1.51". Corner bumped, small chips to the emulsion around the edges, light stains & soil.
  - Nugent, Grace & Bruce with Unidentified Man, April, 1961; "1 35mm Color Slide with an Enlargement (8" x 10"); 1 Photograph (5" x 7") " (Box 90)
    Photos by Raymond Jenkins
  - Nugent, Pauline (Williams) -- RBN's Mother, 1940s; 4 Snapshots (Box 90)
    3 of the snapshots are stamped on the verso "Marr, 65 Jane St. / New York 14, N.Y. -- WA. 9-7921" with "Chas --" inked in.
  - Nugent, Richard Henry, Jr. (RBN's Father) with the Clef Club Quartet, ca 1910; 1 Studio Photograph (9.8" x 6.8") (Box 90)
    Flaking emulsion. VERY FRAGILE.
  - Ortiz, Tony (Cousin of Jesus Sanabria), 4 Photographs (4" x 5.4"); 1 Photograph (3.3" x 5") (Box 90)
    Color photographs. Fine condition. Ortiz is not wearing a shirt.
  - Paparchontis, Constantine (Gus Papas), 1976; 1 Snapshot (Box 90)
  - Paul, Louise, 1 Snapshot (Box 90)
  - Perez, Angelo, 1950s; "14 Photographs (5.5" x 8" to 8" x 10") 10 Photographs (3.5" x 5"); 4 Small Photographs" (Box 90)
  - Perez, Cantor, 1 Poloroid Snapshot (Box 90)
  - Perez, Jerry & Family, 1975; 16 Snapshots (Box 90)
  - Plumeri, Vince, 1966; 4 Photographs (4" x 5" & 5" x 7") (Box 90)
  - Pomer, "Kid" & Jean Daniel, 1970; 1 Photograph 3.5" x 4.7" (Box 90)
    Nude physique photo
  - Ratliff, Autry Davis, 1981; 1 Head Shot 8" x 9.8") (Box 90)
    Inscribed on the verso: "Mr.Bruce Nugent / From / Autry Davis Ratliff / This is a very good day. I shared a little a little of their past. / June 3, 1981
  - Real, Henri, 3 Headshots (8" x 10") (Box 90)
    Inscribed to Ray (Raymond Jenkins)
  - Riley, James Merreman, 1 Publicity Photo (8" x 10") (Box 90)
    Inscribed "To Bruce / Much Love / Jay". Riley is an actor.
  - Rivera, Eduardo, 1959; i Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 90)
    Nude photograph, probably by Bernard Kay
  - Rocco, Joe, 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 90)
    Commercial nude physique photograpy by Heyne, NYC. 1/8" x 3/4" chip of emulsion missing from the top edge, else fine.
  - Rossi, Zaro, 1954; 2 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 90)
    Commercial physique photos. Glued back-to-back to a piece of paper.
  - Sanabria, Jesus, 2 Poloroid snapshots (Box 90)
  - Sansone, Tony, 1930s; 23 Photographs (Various sizes) (Box 90)
    Original physique photographs, originally sold by Sansone. Some of the images appear in books he distributed. Condition varies, mostly very good or better.
  - Sansone, Tony, "3 Photographs (Various sizes) " (Box 90)
    2 of the photographs are by Volpe / N.Y. The third (4.2" x 8.3") is inscribed to Bernard Kay by Sansone
  - Savarino, Sal, 1965; 1 Photograph (10" x 8") (Box 91)
    Nude physique photo. One corner creased, else very good
  - Thomas, Vernon, 1 Headshot (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Labeled "Vernon Thomas / American Model Agency". Small stain in the margin, else very good.
  - West, Dorothy (?), 1929 (?); 1 Small Snapshot (Box 91)
    Young black woman sitting on the rail of a ship. Similar to photos of RBN on the voyage of the Porgy cast to England in 1929. Identification is tentative, but most likely accurate.
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea), "2 Snapshots; 2 Photographs (4.5" x 6.5") 1 Headshot (8" x 10")" (Box 91)
    One of the photographs is signed on the verso with note that indicates that Thompson himself printed it.
  - Tomas, Enrico, 1 Photograph (6.5" x 9") (Box 91)
    Commercial physique photograph. Stamped "Studio ARAX" (Paris) on the verso.
  - Ullrick, Artie & Riccie ------, 1 Photograph (10" x 8") (Box 91)
    Two nude men in bed. Enlarged snapshot; out of focus.
  - Wagner, Martin, 1969; 1 Photograph (4" x 4") (Box 91)
    Photo by James W. Thompson. Soiled. One corner creased.
  - Wilkins, Roy, 1 Headshot (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Photo by KLZ - TV / Channel 7 / Denver" on the verso. One corner creased, emulsion cracked.
  - Windsor, Mary (Queen Mary), 1940s; 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Queen Mary flanked by George VI (?) and Lord Mountbatten (?) with two soldiers. Poor condition--roach marks, tears, stains, cracks
  - Zinsudra, ------, 3 Photos (8" x 10"); 4 Photographs (5" x 7") (Box 91)
    Nude physique photographs of a black male by Bernard Kay. One large photo soiled, another with short cracks in the emulsion.
  - ------, Dino, 1 Headshot (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Black male. Inscribed to RBN
  - ------, Howard, 1 Head Shot (6.2" x 8") (Box 91)
    Soldier. Inscribed "For a nice person / Howard". Poor condition. Wrinkled, creased, taped to a flimsy paper frame
  - ------, Irving, "5 Photographs (3.6" x 4.5"); 1 Photograph (4.8" x 6.7") 1 Photographs (1.1" x 1.2"); 1 Photograph (1.4" x 1.5")" (Box 91)
    Commercial physique photographs by Albert & Otto Schaffenberg, NYC. One is ijnscribed "To BRUCE / A GREAT ARTIST & A Great Guy / Irving" Overall, near fine.
  - ------, Jule, 2 Booth Photos (3" x 2.7"; 3" x 3") (Box 91)
    Inscribed "For Bruce / Jule" and "For Narcissus / Jule
  - ------, Zane, 1 Photograph (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Photograph of a young man inscribed "To Bruce / To Hell with everyone / Zane
  - ------, ------ (Sandy Bruce?), 1880s?; 1 Studio Portrait (3.9" x 5.5") (Box 91)
    Portrait of a distinguished, handsome light-skinned Black man, ca 30-35 years old, with a pince-nez and a waxed mustache. Mounted on brown-gray cardboard that has deteriorated.
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified), 7 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Nude physique photos of various models, some probably by Bernard Kay
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified), 9 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Nude photographs of an unknown model by Bernard Kay. Labels on the verso of some of them make reference to the Gilgamesh legend.
  - ------, ------ (Uniddentified), 4 Photographs (8" x 10"); 1 Photograph (5.5" x 8.1") (Box 91)
    Nude photographs of a young Hispanic (?) man by Bernard Kay
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified), "15 Photographs (8" x 10") 3 Photographs (ca 6.5" x 8.5")" (Box 91)
    Photographs of unidentified young men.
  - ------, ------, 6 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 91)
    Nude physique photographs of a single model.
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified), 6 Photograps (Various sizes) (Box 92)
    Unidentified women
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified), 13 Photographs (Various sizes) (Box 92)
    Physique photographs of unidentified models, some by Bernard Kay
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Man), 2 Photographs (8" x 10"); 1 Photograph 5" x 7") (Box 92)
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Man), 8 Poloroid Snapshots (Box 92)
    Young man--clothed & nude. Photos by RBN.
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Young Men), Feb 1955 - June 1955; 13 Photographs (2.8" x 3.6") (Box 92)
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Young Men), 54 Photographs (Various sizes) (Box 92)
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Young Men), 7 Photographs (Various Sizes) (Box 92)
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified People), 12 Photographs (Various Sizes) (Box 92)
  - Various Subjects, 12 Photographs (Various sizes) (Box 92)
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Children), 1957; 3 Snapshots (3" x 2.4") (Box 92)
    San Juan, PR
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Young Man with a Shaved Head), Aug 1971; 4 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 92)
    Photographs by Warren Marr II. One of them was used by Nugent as the basis for an excellent portrait.
  - ------, ------ (Group of Unidentified Intellectuals), 2 Photographs (10" x 8") (Box 92)
    Elegantly dressed men, dowdy women sitting aound a corner restaurant table. One photograph includes a young black man who may be Nugent. The group looks quite British.
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified Young Man), 2 Photographs (3.6" x 4.5" & 4.7" x 6.6") (Box 92)
    By Bernard Kay.
  - Unidentified Nude, 3 Photographs (4.8" x 6.1") (Box 92)
    Pornographic photographs of a slim, tattooed young man with an erection by Bernard Kay.
  - ------, ------ (Unidentified), 3 Photographs (8" x 10") (Box 92)
    Physique
  - Porgy Cast, March 1929; 1 Photograph (27" x 10") (Box 93 (Broadside))
    Panoramic photograph of the cast of Porgy outside the Apollo theater on the Boardwalk in Atlantic City. Brilliantly clear image. Mounted on acid-free matte board. A few wrinkles, else fine.
- Books, 1931-1994; Series XII; (1 box)
  - Black History Museum Committee, eds. Sterling A. Brown: A UMUM Tribute. Philadelphia: Black History Museum UMUM Publishers, 1982., First edition. Very good in wrappers with some light stains on the covers. (Box 94)
    Inscribed to RBN by James G. Spady, one of the contributors. With a drawing of Brown by Lois Mailou Jones, reproduced on glossy stock, laid in. Table of contents also laid in.
  - Thompson, James W. (Abba Elethea). The Antioch Suite-Jazz. Detroit: Lotus Press, 1980., Stained in wrappers. (Box 94)
    First edition. Inscribed to Nugent by the author and dated 1980.
  - Thompson, James W. First Fire: Poems 1957-1960 London: Paul Bremen, 1970, Slightly age toned, else near fine in wrappers. (Box 94)
    Inscribed to Nugent and dated 16 Dec 1970 by the author.
  - Cullen, Countee. Copper Sun. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1927., First edition, with G-B on the copyright page. (Box 94)
    Good to very good with chipped corners and a soiled spine. Inscribed "For Richard Bruce, Actor-poet, and the most leisurely person I know / Sincerely, / Countee Cullen".
  - Cuney, William Waring. Storefront Church. London: Paul Bremen, 1973. Volume 23 in the Heritage series., Near fine in wrappers. (Box 94)
    Inscribed "For Bruce /and the Harlem Renaissance--/ For Pete / and Pete, Peaches, and Duke--/Sincerely, / Waring / 4/23/74".
  - Ives, Howard Colby. The Song Celestial. Chicago: The Landon Press, 1938., Good to Very Good. Spine tanned. (Box 94)
    Inscribed "To Bruce / in memory of my father / Howard Colby Ives / and because / our Brucie is to-day / thirty-five years old -- / affectionately - / Muriel --- [Ives Barrow] / July 2nd 1941.
  - Gwynne, James, editor. Steppingstones: A Literary Anthology Toward Liberation. Winter, 1983. Malcolm X: A Tribute., Very good (+) in wrappers. (Box 94)
    Inscribed to RBN by Ishmael Reed on p. 5.
  - Southern Senses: Echoes from the Clark College Writers' Workshop/Conference, Fine in wrappers (Box 94)
    Inscribed "Bruce / a celebration from my workshops / James" [James W. Thompson]
  - Thompson, James W. You Are Alms. Np: Fire Publications, 1970., Single sheet, folded to make a brochure. Very good, with light stains and a small scorched spot on the rear cover. (Box 94)
    Inscribed "Bruce: / Father of myself / running deeper. / Love, / James W. Thompson / 28 Mar. 71
  - Van Notten, Eleonore. Wallace Thurman's Harlem Renaissance. Leiden: [The Author], 1994, Fine in wrappers. (Box 94)
    Doctoral Thesis, University of Leiden. With the program for the thesis defense laid in.
  - Schlick, Robert. Klov: A Lyric by Robert Schlick. Peekskill on Hudson: F. B., 1931, One of 30 copies. Light waterstains on the cover, else very good in wrappers. (Box 94)
- Audiovisual materials, 1983-1987; Series XIII; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 95 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Nugent, Richard Bruce. Interviews with Thomas Wirth, June-September 1983; 15 90-minute audiocassettes
    - #1, 1983 June 19; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614772)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - #2, 1983 June 19-24; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614780)
    - #3, 1983 June 24; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614798)
    - #4, 1983 June 27; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614806)
    - #5, 1983 June 27; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614814)
    - #6, 1983 June 30; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614822)
    - #7, 1983 June 30-July 6; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614830)
    - #8, 1983 July 6; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614848)
    - #9, 1983 July 8; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614855)
    - #10, 1983 July 8-August 7; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614863)
    - #11, 1983 August 7; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614871)
    - #12, 1983 August 10; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614889)
    - #13, 1983 September 2-4; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614897)
    - #14, 1983 September 4-5; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614905)
    - #15, 1983 September 5; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614913)
  - Hofstra University. Panel Discussion at Harlem Renaissance Conference, 3 May 1985; 1 (Box 95 (Oversize), Item barcode 39002104614921)